Right.
はい。
So,
ということで
today, rather than us just talking,
今日はね、あの、私たちが喋るというよりかはね、
we wanted you to really watch this scene, so we just had you
このシーンをしっかり見ていただきたいということで見ていただき
take a look at it.
ましたけれども
Thank you all for sharing so many of your thoughts in the comments.
皆さん感想すごくコメントで書いてくださっていてありがとうございます。
Based on this story, we'd like to talk about
私たちもね、このお話を踏まえて、こう、ま、
how we approached our performances as actors.
演者としてどういう風に演じたかなとかそういうのをお話できたら
Please keep in mind that these are just our personal thoughts on what we focused on while acting,
なって思うんですけれども、ま、あくまで演じる時に心がけていたことというねエピソードですのでそれを
so please keep that in mind...
胸に
...as you listen. First, regarding Ena, for this Episode 8—
聞いていただきたいんですけれども、まず絵名的には、ま、今回のこの8話をですね
well, not just Episode 8, but taking the previous story into account too—
ま、8話だけじゃなくて今回のあの、前回のストーリーも踏まえて
when I tried to put myself in Ena's shoes
自分がこう絵名の立場に立って物考えてみた
and think about things, I really couldn't find a "correct" answer at all.
時に、やっぱり正解っていうのは全然見つけることができなくてこう実際
I wondered how she would actually feel,
どういう風に思うんだろうとかどんな
or how she would act. I thought about it over and over, staring at the script from Ena's perspective until...
風に行動するんだろうって考えて考えて絵名の立場になってみてこう台本をずっと見つめ続けていての
...the final
最後の8
Episode 8.
話だったんですけれども
I got swept up in the atmosphere, and it was a bit...
雰囲気に引っ張られてしまってなんかこうちょっと
how should I put it... I was on the verge of tears.
こう何でしょうねな、涙涙のほうというかうん、
Emotionally, I just felt like I was going to...
どうしても行きたくなったりとかこう気持ち的にね、こうどう
well, the tears were just overflowing.
してもき、涙が溢れちゃうというか感じだったんですけど、
There were detailed instructions like, "Cry here," or "Sniffle here."
ここで泣いて、ここで鼻をすすってみたい
So based on that, I first thought about how to play Ena as she cries here,
な、こう細かい指示もあって、で、それを踏まえて私は最初じゃあここで涙を流す絵名、
and how I should approach it.
どういう風に演じようっ
When I thought about it, I really wanted to tell Mizuki, "You're fine just the way you are,"
て思った時に本当にこうあなたはあなたのままでいいんだよ、
and "You're important to me." I was planning my performance
あなたが大切なんだよっていうことを瑞希に伝え
with that single-minded focus in mind.
たいっていう一心でこう演じるプランを考えていたし、
I wanted to act with my own honest feelings,
自分も自分の正直な心でそういう風に演じたいなって思っ
but when I actually went to the recording session,
たんですけどこう実際収録に行って
after they heard my first take, the director told me they wanted a "catfight."
聞いていただいた後にディレクションでキャットファイトがしたいって言わ
That's what they said.
れたんですね。
When they said they wanted to see a catfight between Mizuki and Ena, I asked, "So I don't have to cry?
で、瑞希と絵名のキャットファイトが見てみたいって言われた時にじゃあ泣かなくていいんですね
I can actually
戦っていいん
fight with them?"
ですねっていう風にお話をしたわけですよ。
Then I started wondering what kind of Ena would do that, and it suddenly hit me.
で、じゃあそうなる絵名ってどういう絵名だろうって思った時に私はすごくハッとして
Ena even says, "I haven't changed,"
絵名は変わってないって
right there in the script.
言ってんじゃん台本でって思ったんですね。
My original plan and the stage directions were both very lovely,
で、私が今までやろうとしていたり台本のト書きにあったプランもとても素敵なんですけど、
but that came from
でもそれって瑞希
caring about Mizuki so much that I was being overly considerate. I felt like that wasn't right...
を大切に思うがあまり必要以上に気にかけていっしまってでもそれって違うような、
I realized that if it were Ena,
絵名だったら違うなって思っ
she would do things differently.
たんですよ。
Of course, those feelings of caring are very important,
そ、大切に思う気持ちは本当に大、大事ですけど、
but because she cares, she should be able to clash with them and ask,
でも大切に思うからこそ自分の気持ちをぶつけたりとか何で
"Why don't you understand?" I realized that having their usual fight
伝わらないのっていつも通りに喧嘩することが
was actually the important part.
大事だったんだなっていう風に、なんかこうやっぱり
Since I'm not Ena myself,
絵名じゃないから
looking at it from the outside makes it seem like this grand ordeal—and the problem itself is something only Mizuki can truly understand—
全部を見てるとなんか壮大なことのように確かに問題自体は本当に瑞希にしかわからないことだけど、
but I think...
でも多分
For the two of them—and for Ena—it was probably just a fight.
2人にとって絵名にとっては喧嘩ってだけで多分、
This is just my opinion, but even though we made it out to be
私が思うだけですけどでもなんか私たちが傍から見てすごく
a huge deal from an outsider's perspective...
大ごとにしてしまったけど
...I interpreted it as the first time these two finally clashed with someone,
今までちゃんとしてこなかった人とぶつかるっていうことを初めて2人はしたんだなっ
and I kept that in mind while performing the role.
ていう解釈でなるほどっていう風に思いながら演じさせていただきました。
I was actually worried because I couldn't quite connect
なのでイラストとあまりにもこう想像していたイラストと
the angry Ena I'd imagined with the illustration...
怒ってる絵名っていうのが結びつかなくて大丈夫かなっ
...but it turned out so wonderful that I'm just relieved.
て思ってたんですがすごい素敵になっていてホッとしているというのが
That's how I feel.
気持ちでございました。
Yes.
はい。
Well, Episode 8 was like that, but since we're here,
ま、そんな8話もありつつ、ま、せっかくなのでね、
I'd also like to hear about the banter with Mizuki. Do we have time for that,
瑞希の掛け合いっていうのもあってお話聞きたいなっていうところではあるんですがいけますかね、
schedule-wise?
時間的に?
Well, from Mizuki's perspective,
ねま、瑞希的にはやっぱり
you really can't miss Episode 8 in either case.
ま、どっちの8話も見逃せないですよね。
In the previous Episode 8, Ena was often at a loss for words,
結構前回の8話は絵名結構こう言葉が見つからないっていうのもあるんで、
so for me, that was really all there was to it.
私的にはその、もうただそれだけだっ
But what about you?
たのであれですけど、どうですか?
Mizuki-chan, right...
瑞希ちゃんそうですね。
To talk about it a bit... for the previous event, "Where Shall This Path Lead?", and this one,
ちょっとお話しさせていただくとその私結構前回の傾曲の道はいずこへと今回のね、
I actually asked to record standing up.
収録の仕方で立って撮らせ
I was hesitating until the very last minute, though.
てくださいっていうか結構ねギリギリまで迷って、
Because when it comes to voice acting,
ていうのもちょ、私自身が、あの、ま、アフレコのスタイルっ
I'm the type who feels I need to really "act" with my voice,
てなるとその声でお芝居しなきゃって思っちゃうタイプだからこそ立ったほうが、
so standing up makes it feel more like being on stage.
ちょ、舞台と一緒だからできる
I thought about it, and well...
かなと思ったんですけど、その
when you're crying, your legs naturally lose their strength.
泣くってなると足に、ま、もちろん力は入らなくなるっていうのもあって
So, to really focus on the voice,
いい意味でその声に集中するってなっ
I thought it might be better to sit down while recording.
たら座ってたほうがいいのかなと思い撮らせていただいて、
For Episode 8 of the previous event, "The Path to the Curved Melody"...
前回の傾曲の道はいずこへの8話をはその私の
my initial plan was that even while crying,
最初作ってたプランニングは泣きながらでもその
they would still be able to speak clearly.
ちゃんと言葉は話っていうイメージだったので、
But I got direction saying, "I want you to cry more," so
もっと泣いてほしいですっていうディレクションがあって、そっ
I probably did about three or four more takes after that.
から多分34本くらい撮って
I recorded both that time and this time
そこから私は稔ちゃんのセリフを聞かずに、
without hearing Minori-chan's lines, so I heard their conversation
あの、前回も今回も撮ってるので、皆さんと同じタイミングでその
at the same time as all of you. I was like, "Oh,
2人の掛け合いを聞いたっていうのもあって、あ、
so this is how the final scene turned out!"
こんな風に作品として仕上がったんだなっていう風に、
And well,
あの
because of that, I feel like I was able to give it my absolute all.
思えたので、あの、私的には、あの、全力を尽くさせていただいたなと思っております。
We see each other quite often even if we don't meet during recording,
なんか結構こう会ったりはするので、収録では会えないんですけど、
so we're always asking each other, "How did you record that?"
結構どうやって撮った?
or "What kind of direction did you get?"
どうやって言われた?
We talk about that all the time. And, well...
みたいなのずっと話しててなんかこれはね、
this is just a small request for the staff, but
スタッフさんにちょっとちょっとした要望なんですけど、なんかこう
we were saying how wonderful it would be if we could record together in the same studio one day.
いつか掛け合いで一緒に同じスタジオに入って撮れたら素敵だねっていうのは言っていて、
The ProSeka staff
なんかすごくプラの
really respect the actors' performances, so as
セカンドスタッフさん、演者さんのお芝居すごくリスペクトしてくださるからこそなんかまた
Mizuki and Ena grow,
成長した瑞希と絵
they might run into another big wall again.
名がまた何か大きな壁にぶつかるかもしれないし、
But they might take action to save someone,
でも誰かを助けるために動くかもしれないし、
and I hope that next time,
なんかそういう
we can have a back-and-forth in a wonderful scene like that.
素敵なシーンで今度は一緒に掛け合えたらいいななんて思ってます。
And even without that, we're kind of like, "We really nailed it!"
で、それがない中でこうようはまったなっていうちょっとうちら、
Or rather, "Yay!" in a way, but...
いや、イェーイみたいなとこもありますけど、
Anyway, we've talked quite a bit,
はい、じゃあこんな感じでお話ししましたが、
but it's almost time, so let's all watch
もうそろそろ時間ですのでここからはアフターライブを皆さんで
the AfterLive together.
見ていきたいと思います。
Private...
プライベート